# Ishaan Shah

E-mail: ishaan.shah@research.iiit.ac.in \* GitHub: ishaan.shah Website: ishaan.shah.xyz \* LinkedIn: ishaan.shah

#### Introduction

I am a MS graduate from IIIT Hyderabad. During my Master's, I was supervised by Prof. P. J. Naryanan and co-advised by Dr. Adrien Gruson and Dr. Luis Gamboa. My research revolves around light transport theory and material appearance modeling. Specifically, I am interested in combining stochastic and analytic methods to improve rendering algorithms. Check out my publications to get to know more about my research.

### Work experience

Research Assistant

Advisor: Prof. P.J. Narayanan

July 2021 - May 2024

• Worked on application of analytical and neural methods for solving complex light transport.

• Was involved in other publications related to Gaussian Splatting and Neural Fields.

Teaching Assistant

Course: Computer Graphics

IIIT-H

IIIT-H

January 2024 - February 2024

• Helped in making assignments and setting examinations.

Research Intern IBM Research

Manager: Dr. Prathiba Moogi

April 2021 - July 2021

- Worked on the OpenShift observability stack to find its shortcomings and developed solutions to improve them.
- Was involved in authoring a patent, which was granted by the US Patent Office.

## Student System Administrator

Hyderabad

IIIT-H

March 2021 - December 2023

- Responsibilities include managing, troubleshooting, maintaining, and improving college IT & network infrastructure.
- Migrated the gateway server and edge routers to PfSense from a Linux-based setup.
- Improved the monitoring stack by migrating from Nagios to Prometheus + Grafana.
- Helped in migration of internal nameserver from BIND to PowerDNS.

#### Summer Intern

 $MetaBrainz\ Foundation$ 

May 2020 - August 2020

GSoC 2020

- Worked on ListenBrainz, a website that allows users to track their music listening history and get useful recommendations and statistics.
- My project involved creating statistics and visualizations for the users and the community.
- Read more about the project in this blog

### Education

## M. S. in Computer Science

IIIT-H

Advisor: Prof. P.J. Naraynan Co-Advisor: Dr. Adrien Gruson Co-Advisor: Dr. Luis E. Gamboa

2023-2024

**Thesis topic**: Working on application of analytical methods for enhancing the convergence speed and appearance modeling in light transport simulations.

### B. Tech in Computer Science

IIIT-H

CGPA: 8.9/10

2019-2023

Relevant courses: Computer Graphics, Advanced Graphics: AR & VR, Digital Image Processing, Medical Image Analysis, Statistical Methods in AI.

#### **Publications**

Neural Histogram-Based Glint Rendering of Surfaces With Spatially Varying Roughness

Ishaan Shah, Luis E. Gamboa, Adrien Gruson, P. J. Narayanan  $EGSR\ 2024\ (CGF)$ 

MANUS: Markerless Grasp Capture using Articulated 3D Gaussians

Chandradeep Pokhariya, <u>Ishaan Shah\*</u>, Angela Xing\*, Zekun Li, Kefan Chen, Avinash Sharma, Srinath Sridhar

CVPR 2024

• DiVa-360: The Dynamic Visual Dataset for Immersive Neural Fields

Cheng-You Lu\*, Peisen Zhou\*, Angela Xing\*, Chandradeep Pokhariya, Arnab Dey, <u>Ishaan Shah</u>, Rugved Mavidipalli, Dylan Hu, Andrew Comport, Kefan Chen Srinath Sridhar *CVPR 2024* 

• Combining Resampled Importance & Projected Solid Angle Samplings for Many Area Light Rendering

<u>Ishaan Shah\*</u>, Aakash KT\*, P. J. Narayanan SIGGRAPH Asia 2023 (Technical Communications)

Automated tree generation using grammar & particle system

Aryamaan Jain, Jyoti Sunkara, <u>Ishaan Shah</u>, K. S. Rajan *ICVGIP 2021* 

Application event logging augmentation

 $\underline{\text{Ishaan Shah}},$  Seema Nagar, Pooja Aggarwal, Pratibha Moogi $US\ Patent$ 

#### Technical skills

**Programing Languages** C/C++, CUDA, Python, Javascript

Frameworks Vulkan, OpenGL

Tools Git, GNU/Linux, LATEX

#### **Project**

Ray Tracer

GitHub 2022

- A minimal GPU accelerated ray tracer written in OpenGL.
- Features include next-event estimation, GGX BSDF, BVH acceleration, and more.

### **HPG Student Competition**

GitHub 2022

Optimized the given ray tracer code to reduce variance and increase speed.

• Applied various optimizations ranging from better light sampling to faster intersection tests.

## ${\bf Skye} \,\, {\bf Force} \,\,$

GitHub 2022

• A 3D space shooter game built using WebGL.

## Awards and Achievements

- Deans List Awardee
- AIR 3,734 in JEE Mains 2019